Joseff Thomas

Sheffield

 \boxtimes joseffthomas91@gmail.com \bullet $\ ^{\bullet}$ www.jthom.me \bullet $\ ^{\bullet}$ josefft $\ ^{\bullet}$ $\ ^{\bullet}$ josefft $\ ^{\bullet}$ josefft

Skills

Frontend: Backend:

Experience with JavaScript, Vue.js, React and Professional experience with PHP, Codelgniter and iQuery.

Proficient at hand coding HTML and CSS/SASS o Knowledge of object-orientated design, MVC archito web standards.

Experience with frontend frameworks such as Boot Experience with writing SQL for MySQL and using strap, UIKit and Tailwind CSS.
 ORM tools such as ActiveRecord and Propel.

Knowledge of responsive design, accessibility and O Knowledge of interacting with RESTful APIs.
 cross-browser compliance.
 Familiar with Java, Ruby and Python.

Familiar with Webpack.
 Familiar with unit testing and TDD.

Familiar with Composer.

Other Relevant Skills

- Knowledge of source control and have experience with Git.
- o Knowledge in deploying development environments using Vagrant.
- Quick and keen learner, like to keep skills relevant and up to date by self teaching, reading blogs and attending conferences.

Experience

Freelance

Web Developer

Remote/Sheffield

May 2018—Present

www.jthom.me

I have been working with several organisations on a freelance basis.

Peak Climbing Club (2018–2019)

www.peakclimbingclub.co.uk

Developed the new Peak Climbing Club website (www.peakclimbingclub.co.uk) using Bootstrap and Processwire.

Peter and Paul (2018)

 Peter and Paul are a brand design agency, I worked with them on a short contract building websites using ProcessWire, Tailwind CSS and UIKit.

Nahuru (2018)

www.nahuru.com

- Nahuru is a data analytics company, which focuses on audience measurement services for the entertainment and marketing industry.
- Developed their redesigned website (www.nahuru.com) using PyroCMS and Bootstrap.
- Nahuhash developed a search user interface using Vue.js to interact with their 'Search Automation (Sauto)' backend system.

Tonic Works Sheffield

Symfony PHP Developer

November 2017-May 2018

www.tonic.works

My role at Tonic Works has involved working on various SaaS projects within the Legal Tech sector using Symfony and React.

Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Furthering the development of "QuoteXpress" CRM system using Symfony and React.
- Building a PHP API wrapper for the Land Registry SOAP API.

Twinkl Educational Publishing

Sheffield

Web Developer November 2016–November 2017

www.twinkl.co.uk

Twinkl is an online educational resource company with over two million registered users worldwide. My role has involved furthering the development of the Twinkl website and internal systems using PHP and MySQL.

Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Built a help desk ticketing system in order to bring customer support into one place. A part of this made use of the the Gmail API to send and receive emails via the help desk.
- Used the Paypal API to build system to allow colleagues to send payment requests to users and also make refunds through the system.
- Modernised processes in the web team such as using Composer, using Xdebug and switching to PHPStorm.

ToucanTech London

Web Developer

July 2014-November 2016

www.toucantech.com

ToucanTech is community management software for institutions such as schools and universities. It is composed of two major sections, a front end community network portal and an admin portal, which includes a user database, CRM, email engine, CMS and fundraising tools.

Responsibilities and Achievements:

- My role involves working closely with the founders and CTO to develop new features and functionality using PHP,
 Codelgniter and MySQL.
- Some key features that I have developed have included:
 - Photo gallery module, which allows users to upload and view photos on the network.
 - Activity tracker module, which allows school administrators to keep of a log of activities with end users.
 - Various enhancements and bug fixes to keep the networks running smoothly.
- Recruiting and training new junior developers.

Business Because London

Web Developer

September 2013-September 2015

www.businessbecause.com

My role involved furthering the development of the niche networking website, BusinessBecause, a global network for MBA students. The website is built in PHP/Codelgniter, incorporating modules from PyroCMS.

Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Created new features and functionality using PHP, Codelgniter and MySQL as well as updating the front end using HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.
- $\hbox{$\circ$ Simplified the registration process, which allowed people to register using their LinkedIn and/or Facebook accounts. } \\$
- Optimised the website for mobile, using HTML5, CSS3 and Bootstrap, which led to an increase in traffic from mobile users.

Compliance Control Ltd Northwich

Software Developer (Industrial Placement)

June 2011-September 2012

This was an industrial placement as part of my degree. I was involved in developing "ComplianceControl Centre", an electronic document and quality management system for use in the pharmaceutical and life sciences industries. This was written using PHP and an Oracle database. Also included building the front end using standards compliant XHTML, CSS and JavaScript

The Shrewsbury and Telford Hospital NHS Trust

Shrewsbury

IT Technical Support Assistant

June 2010–September 2010

This was a general IT support role, my main duty was replacing and configuring old computers throughout the hospital. In addition, I was also responsible for fixing day to day IT problems for end users.

Education

Aberystwyth University

BSc (Hons) Computer Science

2009-2013

The Thomas Adams Sixth Form

A-Levels 2007–2009

History, IT, Geography

The Thomas Adams School

GCSEs

10 including English and Maths

2002-2007

Interests

My interests include rock climbing, photography, running, cycling and cooking.